screenshotmonitor.com 2015-04-07

# Online employee monitoring and time tracking - Screenshot Monitor

## Privacy Policy

**This Privacy Policy applies to all personally identifiable information obtained from or about the registered users (end user data), and related to or arising from the use of the ScreenshotMonitor.com** We respect your right to privacy and we have provided you this Privacy Policy to inform you how your personal information will be collected, tracked, stored, used, and protected, and to give you choices as to what personal information you wish to share with us. 

### Free user notice

We provide the same standard of handling the personal information to free and commercial users. However, please note that as a free user some parts of this privacy policy may not apply to you. This privacy policy applies to free users only to the extent, to which they provide ScreenshotMonitor.com with personal information. 

### What Information Does ScreenshotMonitor.com Collect and Track?

#### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

The following information may be collected and stored automatically: the IP address from which you access the internet, the date and time, the internet address of the website from which you link directly to our website, the name of the file or the words you search, and the browser you use to access our website. This information is used to measure the number of visitors to various sections of our website and to identify system performance or for server issues. We also use this information to help us expand the coverage of the website and to make the website more useful. This information is not correlated with any personal information and we never disclose it in a form that personally identifies you. 

#### Personal Information Provided by Users

We request personal information when you create a user account, place an order, register a product, request a service, correspond with us, or engage in certain other activities on our website, such as answering a survey or entering a contest. "Personal information" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual. An individual is considered identified or identifiable if it is possible to identify him or her directly or indirectly. We only request personal information which is necessary for us to provide a product or service that you require and we only process the personal information for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy. For example: If you submit an order on-line with us, we ask you for information necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name, address, and credit card number. If you request technical support on-line, we ask you for information necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name address and information about your computer hardware, software (including your License Number), and the nature of the problem you are experiencing. If you wish to create a user account, we ask you for information necessary to keep you informed about ScreenshotMonitor.com products and services with regard to your needs, such as your e-mail address. If you wish to register a product, we ask you for information necessary to respond to your future queries and to provide support, such as your name, surname, e-mail address, and country. You decide whether to proceed with any activity that requests personal information. However, if you do not wish to provide information needed for a transaction, you may not be able to complete it. 

### How Do We Use the Information We Collect and Track?

We use personal information in the following ways and for the following limited purposes: 

  * To provide you with information about product upgrades, new products, services, research on future product ideas or improvements, to send newsletters, informative e-mails or other information which has the nature of business announcements. ScreenshotMonitor.com reserves the right to use customers' contact information to send them information it deems important for the full utilization of its products and services. Every registered customer may choose not to receive such information from ScreenshotMonitor.com by simply replying to any message to that effect (with the exception of messages which are necessary for the functionality of our products and services);
  * To assist us in creating content that is relevant to you;
  * To assist us in creating better, customized products and services to meet your needs;
  * To allow you to purchase and download products, obtain access to services or otherwise engage in activities you select;
  * To help you quickly find software, services, or product information important to you;
  * allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you chose to do so; and
  * To notify you about changes to our service

ScreenshotMonitor.com, including our offices (subsidiaries and affiliates) abroad to which your personal data are made accessible, retain the personal information collected through ScreenshotMonitor.com website, including your personal information that you submit through a registration process, for as long as you are registered at any ScreenshotMonitor.com website through a user account or are a user of ScreenshotMonitor.com products, and for a reasonable time thereafter, unless and until you have recalled your consent with the processing of your personal information. 

### Security

We restrict access to personal information about you to those ScreenshotMonitor.com employees who need to know the information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. If you share a computer with anyone, always log out before leaving a website or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. Unfortunately, no transmission of information over the internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to our website from your computer or the Internet Service Provider, and any transmission is at your own risk. 

### With Whom Do We Share Your Information?

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, **we will not disclose** users’ personal information outside of ScreenshotMonitor.com and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your consent. ScreenshotMonitor.com will expend the maximum effort to protect users' personal information against misuse and will refrain from disclosing it to third parties. Through some ScreenshotMonitor.com websites, by selecting a region (language) option, you may be asked to share your personal information, such as your e-mail contact, with selected local ScreenshotMonitor.com partners, such as distributors (the full list of which is available at our local websites) so that they can contact you, on our behalf, about ScreenshotMonitor.com products, services or offers that we believe are important to you or your business and to provide you a local technical and customer support. We encourage you to read our partners' privacy policies before providing your personal information. ScreenshotMonitor.com retains the services of outside contractors to provide limited services on our behalf us, such as shipping products or handling order processing, processing transactions (including credit card transactions), or performing statistical analysis of our services. It may be necessary to share user personal information with these contractors in order to allow them to provide their services. You have the right not to provide the requested information, but in such case you may not be able to receive these services. Those contractors will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service and we require that they keep the personal information of our customers secure and confidential and comply with the Act. We also require that these contractors use our customers' personal information only on behalf of ScreenshotMonitor.com and do not disclose them to third parties or use them for any other purpose. Please be advised that in certain instances it may be necessary for ScreenshotMonitor.com to disclose your personal information if we believe such action is necessary to: **(a)** comply with law or legal process served on ScreenshotMonitor.com; **(b)** protect and defend the rights, property or legitimate interests of ScreenshotMonitor.com (including the enforcement of our agreements); or **(c)** act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of ScreenshotMonitor.com services or members of the public. 

### How Can You Correct Inaccuracies in the Information?

#### Registration

We strive to process only accurate personal information and make a sincere effort to respond to your requests to update or correct your personal information. If you believe that ScreenshotMonitor.com does not have your current personal information, you can update it by contacting ScreenshotMonitor.com. 

### ScreenshotMonitor.com Update Bulletin and Other E-mail Communications

If you do not wish to continue receiving our e-mail newsletters, bulletins, or other information from ScreenshotMonitor.com, you can at any time unsubscribe them in the subject line of your e-mail. Please be aware that our e-mails may include important or useful information about your product, including information about your License Number or the status of your orders or accounts, and that we do not allow our customers to opt out of communication that is required for the functionality of our products and services. 

### Cookies

ScreenshotMonitor.com may use cookies from time to time. A cookie is a unique text file that a website can send to your browser software. Cookies enable a website to tailor information presented to you based on your browsing preferences. ScreenshotMonitor.com may use cookies to personalize your pages at our Service & Support website, or to remember you when you register for products or services. If you do not want ScreenshotMonitor.com to deploy cookies in your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website tries to put a cookie in your browser software. Rejecting cookies may affect your ability to use some of the products and/or services at our website. ScreenshotMonitor.com may also use cookies to track your visit to our website. While our web servers may automatically log your IP address, this information does not identify you and you remain anonymous. We do not correlate this information with your personal information. 

### Links to other companies

From time to time, ScreenshotMonitor.com websites may contain links to and from websites of our partner networks, advertisers or other third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

### Co-branded websites

We also link to co-branded websites that are maintained by ScreenshotMonitor.com and one or more of our business partners. An example of a co-branded website is ScreenshotMonitor.com’s e-shop. When you submit information to one of our co-branded websites, you may be submitting it to both ScreenshotMonitor.com and our business partners and the privacy policies of these co-branded websites may differ from this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on any co-branded website to which you link, and we disclaim any liability for the data processing activities of our business partners which will act as independent data processing controllers. 

### Discussion Groups and Forums

Please remember that information you submit in a discussion group or forum at any ScreenshotMonitor.com website will be deemed public information and is not confidential. There is a risk in such communication venues that various information and data can be collected and used by others. Please be careful and responsible when you are on-line. 

### Changes of Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to amend or update this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice, in particular in response to changes in applicable data protection and privacy legislation. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically to inform yourself of any changes. All updates will be published at this website. In the event there is a major change to the ScreenshotMonitor.com privacy practices, a prominent notice will be posted on our website prior to its implementation. If the change involves the use of your personal information, the notice will contain instructions on how you can opt out of such use. 

### Language

This Privacy Policy was originally prepared in the English language. Although ScreenshotMonitor.com may provide one or more translations for your convenience, the English version will control in the case of any conflict or discrepancy. 

### Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contacts us at http://ScreenshotMonitor.com/contact
